Fausto Lopez

Analytics Manager

Personal Info

Address

110-23 55th Ave 2nd floor Corona New York 11368

Phone

646-639-3360

E-mail

FaustoLopez110@gmail.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/lopezfausto

Hard Skills

Automation

Advanced

Data Visualization

Advanced

Database Knowledge

Good

Languages

₹

Advanced

SQL

Advanced

Python

Good

Javascript

Beginner

Soft Skills

Resourcefulness

Expert

Leadership

Advanced

Creative and resourceful data scientist with 5+ years experience munging, wrangling and analyzing data. Expanded big data analytical processes at the NYC Taxi and Limousine Commission by 50% and increased access to new Key Performance Indicators for a rapidly evolving industry. Developed big data pipelines and migration strategies, built comprehensive dashboards along with multiple databases and increased query and reporting speeds by over 500%. Developed and lead a team of 4 analysts working on over 300 gigabytes of data.

Experience

2016-07 - Data & Analytics Manager

present

Taxi & Limousine Commission of New York

- Design and automate analytical processes to produce internal and public facing metrics on 1,000,000+ taxi trip records, creating Shiny/Tableau dashboards and tracking KPIs
- Pioneered innovative analytical and ETL processes on over 300 GB of data to run parallel computing and speed up queries
- Established and expanded pipelines between SQL Server Database and external data sources that feed into reports
- Lead project to migrate 300 GB of data from SQL Server to Postgres in order to access Postgis geospatial tools and improve dynamic reporting
- Spearheaded \$100,000 landmark Driver Income study leading to first national vehicle cap on ride sharing companies like UBER and LYFT
- Launched Analytics Blog meant to showcase innovative and interesting insights and visualizations on all things taxi related

2015-06 - **Data & Evaluation Manager**

2016-06

Urban Upbound

- Oversaw and managed over 6 separate databases to track outcomes and reporting
- Developed evaluation protocols and analytical tools for testing program models
- Assisted in designing and implementing a study on financial stress as a predictor of financial counseling outcomes
- In partnership with New York Women's Foundation, designed and implemented the Healthy Aging Study, a qualitative report recommending resource upgrades for senior citizens in Far Rockaway

2014-07 - **Monitoring & Evaluation Assistant**

2015-05

Urban Upbound

- Designed and implemented analytical tools
- Developed evaluation protocols for testing program models
- Analyzed data and produced quality reports
- Assisted in survey construction

Education

2009-08 -

Macaulay Honors College at CUNY – Hunter College

2014-05

Bachelor of Arts in Sociology

Masters of Science in Applied Social Research

Publications

2018-06

An Earnings Standard for New York City's App-Based Drivers: Economic Analysis and Policy Assessment